Young Women's Christian Association of Albany, New York; Records apap137
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Photographs, 1911-1995; 5; 2.64 cubic ft.
  This series holds photographs documenting YWCA activities and programs covering 1936 to 1995, particularly the annual Tribute to Women. It consists of color and black and white prints, slides, and negatives. There is tape damage on some prints. The majority of the pictures are from the 1980s and 1990s. One photograph is available for viewing online from the University at Albany Libraries' Digital Collections database.
  One photograph is available for viewing online from the University at Albany Libraries' Digital Collections database
  - Aerobics, Black and White, 1983-1986 (Box 1 (5-Photographs), Folder 1)
  - Aerobics, Black and White, 1987-1989 (Box 1 (5-Photographs), Folder 2)
  - Aerobics, Black and White, 1990-1995; Undated (Box 1 (5-Photographs), Folder 3)
  - Aerobics, Children, 1987; 1989-1990; Undated (Box 1 (5-Photographs), Folder 4)
  - Aerobics, Color, 1987-1990; Undated (Box 1 (5-Photographs), Folder 5)
  - Annual Dinners, 1983; 1985 (Box 1 (5-Photographs), Folder 6)
  - Black History Month Essay Contest, 1980; 1982-1984 (Box 1 (5-Photographs), Folder 7)
  - Black History Month Essay Contest, 1988; 1990; 1992-1993 (Box 1 (5-Photographs), Folder 8)
  - Black History Month Essay Contest, Undated (Box 1 (5-Photographs), Folder 9)
  - Children, 1958-1960; 1962; 1966 (Box 1 (5-Photographs), Folder 10)
  - Children, 1983-1986 (Box 2 (5-Photographs), Folder 1)
  - Children, 1987-1989 (Box 2 (5-Photographs), Folder 2)
  - Children, 1990-1994 (Box 2 (5-Photographs), Folder 3)
  - Children, Undated (Box 2 (5-Photographs), Folder 4-7)
  - Children, Christmas Parties, 1988; 1991; Undated (Box 2 (5-Photographs), Folder 8)
  - Drop-In Child Center, Undated (Box 2 (5-Photographs), Folder 9)
  - Empire State Plaza, Demonstrations, 1984 (Box 2 (5-Photographs), Folder 10)
  - Empire State Plaza, Demonstrations, 1985 (Box 3 (5-Photographs), Folder 1)
  - Empire State Black Arts and Cultural Festival, 1985 (Box 3 (5-Photographs), Folder 2)
  - Fire Trucks Program, 1990; 1992; 1994; Undated (Box 3 (5-Photographs), Folder 3)
  - Gallery Exhibits, 1978-1979; Undated (Box 3 (5-Photographs), Folder 4)
  - Garage Sale, 1984-1985; 1987-1989 (Box 3 (5-Photographs), Folder 5)
  - Garage Sale, 1990; 1992 (Box 3 (5-Photographs), Folder 6)
  - Golden Rule Awards, 1990 (Box 3 (5-Photographs), Folder 7)
  - Great Escape Trip, 1992 (Box 3 (5-Photographs), Folder 8)
  - Group Activities, 1970-1979 (Box 3 (5-Photographs), Folder 9)
  - Group Activities, 1980-1983; 1985-1989 (Box 3 (5-Photographs), Folder 10)
  - Group Activities, 1990; Undated (Box 3 (5-Photographs), Folder 11)
  - Halloween Parties, 1987-1989; Undated (Box 4 (5-Photographs), Folder 1)
  - Indoor Sports, 1936; 1944; 1980; Undated (Box 4 (5-Photographs), Folder 2)
  - Martial Arts, 1960; 1987; 1989; 1993; Undated (Box 4 (5-Photographs), Folder 3)
  - Mayor's Office Proclamation, 1988 (Box 4 (5-Photographs), Folder 4)
  - Mom and Tot Group, 1984-1986 (Box 4 (5-Photographs), Folder 5)
  - Negatives, 35mm, 1975; 1986; Undated (Box 4 (5-Photographs), Folder 6)
  - Negatives, 35mm, Various Activities, Undated (Box 4 (5-Photographs), Folder 7-10)
  - Negatives, Film Size 110 and 126, Various Activities, Undated (Box 5 (5-Photographs), Folder 1)
  - People, Identified, 1948; 1950; 1952; 1957-1969 (Box 5 (5-Photographs), Folder 2)
  - People, Identified, 1983-1988; 1990; 1992-1993 (Box 5 (5-Photographs), Folder 3)
  - People, Identified, Undated (Box 5 (5-Photographs), Folder 4-5)
  - People, Unidentified, 1980-1981; 1984-1986 (Box 5 (5-Photographs), Folder 6)
  - People, Unidentified, 1987-1989 (Box 5 (5-Photographs), Folder 7)
  - People, Unidentified, 1990-1993 (Box 5 (5-Photographs), Folder 8)
  - People, Unidentified, Undated (Box 5 (5-Photographs), Folder 9)
  - People, Unidentified, Undated (Box 6 (5-Photographs), Folder 1-4)
  - Slides, Aerobics, Children, Christmas, Essay Contest, Swimming, Undated (Box 6 (5-Photographs), Folder 5)
  - Summer Activities, 1961; 1971 (Box 6 (5-Photographs), Folder 6)
  - Summer Fun Day Camp, 1987; 1990; 1992 (Box 6 (5-Photographs), Folder 7)
  - Swimming, 1944; 1959; 1983; 1985-1989; 1991-1992 (Box 6 (5-Photographs), Folder 8)
  - Swimming, Undated (Box 6 (5-Photographs), Folder 9-10)
  - Tribute to Women, Ceremony and Honorees, 1980; 1982 (Box 7 (5-Photographs), Folder 1)
  - Tribute to Women, Ceremony and Honorees, 1983-1984 (Box 7 (5-Photographs), Folder 2)
  - Tribute to Women, Ceremony and Honorees, 1985 (Box 7 (5-Photographs), Folder 3)
  - Tribute to Women, Ceremony and Honorees, 1986 (Box 7 (5-Photographs), Folder 4)
  - Tribute to Women, Ceremony and Honorees, 1987 (Box 7 (5-Photographs), Folder 5)
  - Tribute to Women, Ceremony and Honorees, 1988 (Box 7 (5-Photographs), Folder 6-7)
  - Tribute to Women, Ceremony and Honorees, 1989 (Box 7 (5-Photographs), Folder 8-9)
  - Tribute to Women, Ceremony and Honorees, 1990 (Box 7 (5-Photographs), Folder 10)
  - Tribute to Women, Ceremony and Honorees, 1992 (Box 8 (5-Photographs), Folder 1)
  - Tribute to Women, Ceremony and Honorees, 1993 (Box 8 (5-Photographs), Folder 2)
  - Tribute to Women, Ceremony and Honorees, 1994 (Box 8 (5-Photographs), Folder 3)
  - Tribute to Women, Ceremony and Honorees, Undated (Box 8 (5-Photographs), Folder 4)
  - Workshops, 1983-1984; 1987-1990 (Box 8 (5-Photographs), Folder 5)
  - Workshops, Undated (Box 8 (5-Photographs), Folder 6)
  - YWCA Buildings, Interior and Exterior, 1955; 1980; 1987-1989 (Box 8 (5-Photographs), Folder 7)
  - YWCA of the USA, 1911-1912; 1918-1919; Undated (Box 8 (5-Photographs), Folder 8)
- Memorabilia, Undated; 6; 7.71 cubic ft.
  This series holds a number of artifacts, banners, handkerchiefs, videotapes, a framed painting, and framed embroidery. Artifacts include pins, posters, ornaments, a gavel, brass plates, and an imprinter with the Albany YWCA seal.
  Arranged by Material.
  - Biblical Quote, Framed Embroidery, 1976 (Box 1 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 1)
  - Arab Cookbook in English, Undated (Box 2 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 1)
  - Australian YWCA, Correspondence, 1958 (Box 2 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 2)
  - Baghdad YWCA, Correspondence, 1958 (Box 2 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 3)
  - Handkerchief, Australian Flowers, ca. 1950s (Box 2 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 4)
  - Handkerchief, Australian Flowers, ca. 1950s (Box 2 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 5)
  - Handkerchief, Australian Koala, ca. 1950s (Box 2 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 6)
  - Handkerchief, Australia Winter Olympics Design, 1956 (Box 2 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 7)
  - Handkerchief, New South Wales Design, ca. 1950s (Box 2 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 8)
  - Handkerchief, Nigerian Design, ca. 1950s (Box 2 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 9)
  - Handkerchief, Queensland Design, ca. 1950s (Box 2 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 10)
  - Nigeria YWCA, Correspondence, 1958 (Box 2 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 11)
  - 8mm Tape, unidentified, Undated (Box 3 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 1)
  - 31st National Convention, Chicago, VHS Tape, 1988 (Box 3 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 2)
  - Advertising/Promos, 3/4" Master Tape, 1989 (Box 3 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 3)
  - Celebrating 100 Years, VHS Tape, 1988 (Box 3 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 4)
  - Public Service Announcements, 3/4" Master Tape, 1988 (Box 3 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 5)
  - Public Service Announcements, 3/4" Master Tape, 1989 (Box 3 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 6)
  - Public Service Announcements Memo, 1988 (Box 3 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 7)
  - Purpose Study, YWCA of the USA, VHS Tape, 1988-1991 (Box 3 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 8)
  - Services and Fund Raising Promo, VHS Tape, 1988 (Box 3 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 9)
  - Tribute to Women Ceremony, VHS Tape, 1992 (Box 3 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 10)
  - Tribute to Women Ceremony, Part 2, VHS Tape, 1992 (Box 3 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 11)
  - YWCA Retirement Fund, VHS Tape, 1989 (Box 3 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 12)
  - YWCA Today, VHS Tape, 1988 (Box 3 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 13)
  - Brass Ornaments, Undated (Box 4 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 1)
  - Brass Plaque, 1922 (Box 4 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 2)
  - Brass Plaque, 1926 (Box 4 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 3)
  - Brass Plaque, Undated (Box 4 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 4)
  - Brass YWCA pins, Undated (Box 4 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 5)
  - Brass YWCA Pins, White and Blue, Undated (Box 4 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 6)
  - International Women's Day, Patch, Undated (Box 4 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 7)
  - New York State Council of YWCAs, Gavel, Undated (Box 4 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 8)
  - "Y-Teen" Stickers, Undated (Box 4 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 9)
  - YWCA of the USA, Pin, 1993 (Box 4 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 10)
  - YWCA stickers, Undated (Box 4 (6-Memorabilia), Folder 11)
  - Body Conditioning Class, Poster, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 1)
  - Business Club Dining, Poster, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 2)
  - Cafeteria, Poster, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 3)
  - Drawing of YWCA Building, 1989 (Oversized 1, Folder 4)
  - Good Fellowship, Poster, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 5)
  - Group Photo, 1957 (Oversized 1, Folder 6)
  - Industrial League, Poster, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 7)
  - Photograph of Mrs. C. Marshall Munson, 1964 (Oversized 1, Folder 8)
  - Purpose Statement, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 9)
  - Reprint of Lithograph of 1922 YWCA poster, 1983 (Oversized 1, Folder 10)
  - "Rooms are Cozy", Poster, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 11)
  - Sports Skills Class, Poster, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 12)
  - Thursday Afternoon Club, Poster, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 13)
  - World Fellowship Committee - poster, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 14)
  - YWCA "Invest in Her", Poster, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 15)
  - YWCA Women of the Century Poster, 1985 (Oversized 1, Folder 16)
  - Black History Month, Banner, 1991 (Oversized 2)
  - Centerport United Methodist Church, Felt Banner, Undated (Oversized 2)
  - Gold Ribbon, Undated (Oversized 2)
  - Maroon, Gold, and Silver Striped Banner, Undated (Oversized 2)
  - World of Difference Banner, Undated (Oversized 2)
  - YWCA of Albany Banner, Undated (Oversized 2)
  - YWCA Sheet, Banner, Undated (Oversized 2)
  - Former YWCA Building, Painting, Undated (Oversized 3)
  - Pueblo YWCA, Poster, ca. 1982 (Oversized 3)
  - Tribute to Women, Framed Newspaper, 1994 (Oversized 3)
  - Blueprints of Renovation, 1990 (Oversized 4)
  - YWCA of the USA, Poster, 1983 (Flat-file 1)
  - Our Purpose, Poster, Undated (Flat-file 2)
  - Mrs. Acors Rathbun, Framed Portrait, Undated (Flat-file 3)
  - Seal Imprinter, Undated (Flat-file 3)